<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tanner&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://tanner202.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tanner&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanner202.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Server and Plugin Development</title>
      <link>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/minecraft-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 09:25:15 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/minecraft-plugins/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I talk about my experience learning to create Minecraft Servers and Plugins.
Backstory As a kid I played a lot of video games. I mainly played Minecraft on popular online servers like Mineplex and Hypixel. During these days, I would wake up, hop on a call with my friends, and we would just play games. As I got older, these servers started to fade away and things changed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Analysis: Mineplex The Bridges</title>
      <link>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/game-analysis-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/game-analysis-bridges/</guid>
      <description>New Series In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;m starting a new series where I analyze games! I&amp;rsquo;m going to be breaking these games down into their components. Dissecting what makes them fun and what parts could be improved. These games are going to be anything ranging from board games to video games. In each post of this series I will first give a reason for analyzing the game, a brief description, some of the mechanics, and then my thoughts on what made it fun and finally the problems and potential solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Development: Team or Independent? (Pros and Cons of each)</title>
      <link>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/team-or-independent-pros-and-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 09:44:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/team-or-independent-pros-and-cons/</guid>
      <description>Intro Both working independently and with a team have their upsides and downsides. It depends on your goals and also what is important to you. For example, if you like having control over every aspect of your game you might prefer solo development. However, if you’re willing to sacrifice some creative liberties you might enjoy working with a team. As someone who&amp;rsquo;s been on both sides of this coin, I will share the pros and cons I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Game Development Mistakes that Derailed my Summer</title>
      <link>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/summer-game-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 07:58:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/summer-game-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>Creating a video game takes many skills, especially if you’re doing it solo. In this blog post I will be sharing 5 mistakes that I made when creating a game in the summer of 2023.
1. Make a plan Plans are important in all aspects of life, but it is especially so in game development. Without a plan you can lose sight of what your goal is and go off on tangents doing things that look cool, but don’t actually help with progress towards finishing your game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting Game Development</title>
      <link>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/starting-game-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 08:17:57 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanner202.github.io/posts/starting-game-dev/</guid>
      <description>Modifying Existing Games I started game development around 4-5 years ago creating Minecraft plugins. Modifying an existing game is a great way to get started learning game development because most of the tools are already in place.
If you enjoy any existing games and would like to build off or modify in any way, I definitely recommend it. Games like Roblox are built as easy to use tools to create games but can also be quite powerful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://tanner202.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanner202.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can contact me at: tannerelephant@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
